# **Kyle Myers**

Kitchener, Ontario, Canada 🗣

(902)-233-4466

kylemyers\_292@live.ca

kylemyers.ca ##

github.com/KMyers292 🖸

linkedin.com/in/kyle-myers-2aab0293 in

# **Profile**

Looking for an opportunity to learn and contribute as a junior developer after 10+ years in leadership positions in the construction industry before deciding on a career change.

Spent the last 4 years in school and self-taught, developing skills to become an effective and valued team member. Always striving to improve further, with a willingness to learn new skills and technology as needed.

## **Education**

## **Computer Programming & Analysis Advanced Diploma**

09/2018 - 12/2020

Seneca College – Toronto, Ontario Graduated with Honors and 3.8 GPA

## **Projects**

## **CampNS**

Links: <a href="https://campns.herokuapp.com/">https://campns.herokuapp.com/</a>, <a href="https://campns.herokuapp.herokuapp.com/">https://campns.herokuapp

Environment: JavaScript, Express.js, Node.js, EJS, NoSQL

- Learned to build a full-stack website by creating a site that showcases the best places to camp and stay in the outdoors in Nova Scotia.
- Full CRUD capabilities with a database hosted through MongoDB.
- Worked with weather and yelp APIs to provide accurate forecast and nearby activities for each campground.
- Learned how to create a simple login/logout system with basic security measures.

## **ShopNS**

Links: https://shopns.herokuapp.com/ , https://github.com/KMyers292/ShopNS

Environment: React / Redux, JavaScript, Express.js, Node.js, NoSQL

- Learned React and Redux by creating a mock e-commerce site that displays local items from around Nova Scotia.
- Created an API from scratch for the backend that has full CRUD capabilities with a database hosted through MongoDB.
- Learned to develop a fully functioning shopping cart and checkout system with the PayPal API.
- Created basic sorting and search functionality.

# **Work Experience**

## **Plant Operator**

Stella Jones - Stouffville, Ontario

## 10/2016 - 09/2018 - 05/2020 - 08/2021

- Ran and maintained pressure treating plant as generally the sole operator.
- Adhered to and surpassed extremely tight deadlines, becoming the highest producing plant in Canada.
- Worked with and trained new employees on computer system used to control plant.
- Trained new employees for various jobs around the site.

#### **Lead Hand Scaffolder**

Panels & Pipes - Fort Mackay, Alberta

02/2014 - 01/2016

- Worked both as a small team and independently to complete projects within tight deadlines.
- Responsible for always ensuring the safety and efficiency of the team as the lead hand.
- Coordinated with outside contractors keeping everything running smoothly.

## **Warehouse Supervisor**

Home Hardware – Jeddore, Nova Scotia

02/2008 - 09/2016

- Supervised a small team of people to ensure orders were being completed correctly and on time.
- Responsible for all training of any new employees.
- Ensured warehouse stock was accounted for and depleted stock was ordered on time.
- Worked with customers to make sure their needs were met and made recommendations when necessary.

## **Skills**

React / Redux  JavaScript	Node.js CSS / Sass	Express.js Angular	Python / Django PHP / Laravel